http://www.essm.org/data-privacy/#cookies

Skip to contentContact usPresentationsBecome a Member
ESSMEuropean Society for Sexual Medicine
Search
SocietyWho we areHistoryMembers of the BoardCommitteesYoSeMAESSM BylawsWhat we doAffiliated SocietiesNational Affiliated Societies (NAS)Worldwide Affiliated SocietiesHost a CongressMembershipEducationCalendarESSM WebinarsESSM Workshop WebinarsESSM Statements WebinarsESSM Virtual Meeting 2021ESSM CongressPast CongressesESSM AcademyESSM Academy of Genital SurgeryErectile Dysfunction VideosESSM School of Sexual MedicineMeet the FacultyCertificationsECPSMJCSMESSM Preparation CoursesResearchResearch GrantsFunded ProjectsBasic Scientist Travel GrantsWinnersAwardsPublicationsESSM TodayESSM Position StatementsJournal of Sexual Medicine (JSM)TextbooksAbstract BooksRessourcesRelated JournalsNewsESSM TodaySocietyNewsletter ArchiveSearch Home > Data privacyData privacy
The following information describes the ways we process your personal data that you have provided or we have obtained from other sources.1. WHO IS PROCESSING YOUR DATA?The European Society for Sexual Medicine (“ESSM”, the controller) is registered at c/o RSM UK, Central Square, 5th floor, 29 Wellington Street, Leeds West Yorkshire LS1 4DL, United Kingdom.Best way to contact us is via e-mail: admin@essm.org.2. WHY ARE WE PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA?Your personal data are being processed for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the ESSM. These legitimate interests are listed in the ESSM by-laws and Minutes.3. WHAT TYPE OF INFORMATION IS COLLECTED FROM YOU?The personal information we collect includes your name, email address, professional details (contact address, work affiliation, professional areas of interest and expertise related to personality disorders, publicly available information about your publications, and publicly available professional web pages).4. HOW IS YOUR INFORMATION USED?We may use your information to:send you information related to being a member of the ESSM;carry out our obligations required by law;carry out elections to offices in the ESSM;seek your views or comments on the issues relevant to our organisation and objectives;send you communications related to the issues and actions of the ESSM. These may include information about events, campaigns, appeals, requests for collaboration, or other, related to our objectives;process a nomination that you have made;process a donation that you have made;5. WHERE DO WE GET THE DATA FROM?We have gotten some information about you when you were nominated for membership or when you requested to become a member. We have validated the data from public sources only. You will have the opportunity to add, correct, erase and share the data and restrict the visibility of your data on the members’ section of our website.6. HOW LONG DO WE STORE YOUR INFORMATION?Your data will be stored as long as you are a member of the ESSM. Some information (your name, duration of membership, reasons for ending the membership, if applicable) will be stored as long as the Federation exists.7. HOW ARE YOUR DATA SHARED?We will always share as little as possible and as much as necessary with third parties. Your data can be shared as follows:Your contact details may be visible to other members of the ESSM.Our partner(s) in organizing the ESSM events will get your contact details in order to inform you about upcoming events.Organizers of other congresses or events besides the ones organized by the ESSM may get your name and contact details if members of the ESSM are eligible for reduced fees or special conditions.If we decide to share your information in any other way you will be informed, or your consent will be asked.8. YOUR RIGHTSRight to informationAccording to Article 15 GDPR you have the right to demand a confirmation whether we process your personal data. Should we process your personal data you have the right to be informed about this personal data and further information, which are explained in Article 15 GDPR.Right to rectificationAccording to Article 16 GDPR you have the right to demand immediate rectification of incorrect personal data relating to you. Furthermore, taking into consideration the purposes of the processing you have the right to request the completion of incomplete personal data, also by means of a complementary declaration.Right to erasureYou have the right to demand that we delete all of your stored personal data immediately. We are obligated to delete personal data immediately, provided the conditions of Article 17 GDPR are met. For further information about the details of these conditions we refer to Article 17 GDPR.Right to restriction of processingAccording to Article 18 GDPR you have the right to demand the restriction of processing of your personal data under certain circumstances.Right to data portabilityAccording to Article 20 GDPR you have the right to receive your provided personal data in a structured, common and machine-readable format from us. Furthermore, you have the right to transmit this data to a controller of your choice without any obstruction by us, insofar the processing is based on a consent according to the Articles 6(1)(a) or 9(2)(a) GDPR, as well as it is based on a contract according to Article 6(1)(b) GDPR and the data is processed by the means of automated procedures.Right to objectAccording to Article 21 GDPR you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data that is based on the Articles 6(1)(e) or (f) GDPR. This also applies for a profiling based on these rules.If we process your personal data for direct marketing purposes, you are entitled to object to the processing of your personal data for these purposes. This also applies for profiling that is linked to such direct marketing activities.If you intend to exercise your given rights, please contact us – the controller – directly using the above stated contact information or choose one of the provided options to contact us on an alternative way to inform us. If you have any questions in this respect, please also contact us directly.Right to logde a complaint with a supervisory authorityAccording to Article 77 GDPR you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement, if you consider the the processing of personal data relating to you infringes the GDPR.9. USE AND APPLICATION OF GOOGLE ANALYTICS (WITH THE ANONYMIZER FUNCTION)We have integrated the component of Google Analytics (with the anonymizer function) on this website.Google Analytics is a web analytics service. Web analytics is the collection, gathering, and analysis of data about the behavior of visitors to websites. A web analysis service collects, inter alia, data about the website from which a person has come (the so-called referrer), which sub-pages were visited, or how often and for what duration a sub-page was viewed. Web analytics are mainly used for the optimization of a website and in order to carry out a cost-benefit analysis of Internet advertising.The operator of the Google Analytics component is Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, United States.During the first visit of our websites we invite the data subject to consent the usage of Google Analytics. The data subject’s activities on our websites are not recorded as long as the respective consent has not been given.In addition, the data subject has the possibility of objecting to a collection of data that are generated by Google Analytics, which is related to the use of this website, as well as the processing of this data by Google and the chance to preclude any such. For this purpose, the data subject must download a browser add-on under the link tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout and install it. This browser add-on tells Google Analytics through a JavaScript, that any data and information about the visits of Internet pages may not be transmitted to Google Analytics. The installation of the browser add-ons is considered an objection by Google. If the information technology system of the data subject is later deleted, formatted, or newly installed, then the data subject must reinstall the browser add-ons to disable Google Analytics. If the browser add-on was uninstalled by the data subject or any other person who is attributable to their sphere of competence, or is disabled, it is possible to execute the reinstallation or reactivation of the browser add-ons.If Google does not provide this Internet browser plugin for the Internet browser or IT system used for your visit, you can deactivate Google Analytics by using this Link: Deactivate Google Analytics. This deactivation only takes effect for the currently used IT system and for the currently used Internet browserFor the web analytics through Google Analytics we use the application “_gat. _anonymizeIp”. By means of this application the IP address of the Internet connection of the data subject is abridged by Google and anonymised when accessing our websites from a Member State of the European Union or another Contracting State to the Agreement on the European Economic Area.The purpose of the Google Analytics component is to analyze the traffic on our website. Google uses the collected data and information, inter alia, to evaluate the use of our website and to provide online reports, which show the activities on our websites, and to provide other services concerning the use of our Internet site for us. This purpose is considered a legitimate interest according to Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.Google Analytics places a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. The definition of cookies is explained above. With the setting of the cookie, Google is enabled to analyze the use of our website. With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and into which a Google Analytics component was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject will automatically submit data through the Google Analytics component for the purpose of online advertising and the settlement of commissions to Google. During the course of this technical procedure, the enterprise Google gains knowledge of personal information, such as the IP address of the data subject, which serves Google, inter alia, to understand the origin of visitors and clicks, and subsequently create commission settlementsThe cookie is used to store personal information, such as the access time, the location from which the access was made, and the frequency of visits of our website by the data subject. With each visit to our Internet site, such personal data, including the IP address of the Internet access used by the data subject, will be transmitted to Google in the United States of America. These personal data are stored by Google in the United States of America. Google may pass these personal data collected through the technical procedure to third partiesThe data subject may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the web browser used and thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Google Analytics from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. In addition, cookies already in use by Google Analytics may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs.Further information and the applicable data protection provisions of Google may be retrieved under https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ and under www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html. Google Analytics is further explained under the following Link https://www.google.com/analytics/.Alphabet Inc. and its subsidiaries (e.g. Google LLC) comply the requirements of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, as well as the Suisse-US Privacy Shield Framework. Further information about these treaties may be retrieved under https://www.privacyshield.gov/.10. USE AND APPLICATION OF YOUTUBE (PRIVACY-ENHANCED MODE)We have integrated components of YouTube on this website. The operating company of YouTube is YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA.YouTube videos on our website are embedded solely by usage of the “privacy-enhanced mode” of YouTube. According to its terms YouTube collects information about the visitors of a website only if they play a video. Further information about this can be accessed at https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/171780?hl=en in the section “Turn on privacy-enhanced mode”.With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a YouTube component (YouTube video) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download a display of the corresponding YouTube component. Further information about YouTube may be obtained under https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/en/. During the course of this technical procedure, YouTube and Google gain knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject.The embedding of YouTube videos serves the purpose of providing informative, additional or scientific contents on this website, which are published by their authors to a broad audience through a public platform (YouTube). This purpose is considered a legitimate interest according to Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.If the data subject is logged in on YouTube, YouTube recognizes with each call-up to a sub-page that contains a YouTube video, which specific sub-page of our Internet site was visited by the data subject. This information is collected by YouTube and Google and assigned to the respective YouTube account of the data subject.YouTube and Google will receive information through the YouTube component that the data subject has visited our website, if the data subject is logged in on YouTube while playing the video on our website. If such a transmission of this information to YouTube and Google is not desirable for the data subject, the delivery may be prevented if the data subject logs off from their own YouTube account before a call-up to our website is made.YouTube’s data protection provisions, available at https://www.google.de/intl/en/policies/privacy/, provide information about the collection, processing and use of personal data by YouTube and Google.Alphabet Inc. and its subsidiaries (e.g. Google LLC, YouTube LLC) comply the requirements of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, as well as the Suisse-US Privacy Shield Framework. Further information about these treaties may be retrieved under https://www.privacyshield.gov/.11. AUTOMATED DECISION MAKING AND PROFILINGWe are processing your data responsibly and neither use automated decision making nor profiling.This policy relating to cookies (hereinafter, the “Cookie Policy”) describes the different types of cookies that we use on our website (hereinafter, the “Website”) and the manner in which you can configure these cookies.We maintain a strict privacy policy and we are committed to being transparent about the technologies that are used on our Website.Insofar as the information collected using cookies constitutes personal data, the provisions of the Privacy Policy shall apply and supplement this Cookie Policy.1. WHAT IS A COOKIE?A “cookie” is a small text file containing information saved by a website on a computer or by a mobile application on a user’s smartphone.Cookies offer the possibility to identify you and to memorize various information in order to facilitate your navigation on a website/a mobile application, to ensure the smooth functioning of these or to make them more effective, for example by memorizing your language preferences.2. WHAT COOKIES ARE USED ON OUR WEBSITE AND WHY?We use different types of cookies for different reasons.Essential cookiesThese cookies are essential for browsing our Website or strictly necessary for the provision of a service specifically requested by a user. The removal of this type of cookies can lead to navigation difficulties and is therefore strongly discouraged.Preference cookiesThese cookies collect information about your choices and preferences and make your navigation more pleasant and personalized. These cookies make it possible to memorize the language chosen during your first visit to our Website in order to personalize it accordingly.Analytics cookiesThese cookies are used to gather information about your use of the Website, in order to improve the content of the Website, make it more suitable to your needs and increase its usability. For example, these cookies show us the most visited pages of the Website or help to identify difficulties that may be encountered during navigation.3. HOW TO CONFIGURE THE COOKIES?You can easily delete, disable or accept cookies from our Website at any time by configuring your browser settings.Each browser (Internet Explorer, Safari, Firefox, Google Chrome, etc.) has its own cookie configuration mode. To learn about the procedure to follow concerning your navigator, visit the site: www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/.If you use different computers, smartphones and/or tablets, do not forget to configure each device so that each of them corresponds to your preferences regarding cookies.4. WILL OUR WEBSITE STILL WORK WITHOUT COOKIES?You will still be able to view our Website, but some interactions may not work normally.If you disable this cookie, the selected products will disappear with each new login session.
MenuData privacy
Our Vision "Sexual Health for Everyone" ContactESSM - European Society for Sexual Medicine c/o RSM UK Central Square 5th floor, 29 Wellington Street Leeds West Yorkshire LS1 4DL Email: admin@essm.org Sign Up for our Newsletter
About ESSMWho we are Members of the Board YoSeMA Membership ESSM CertificationsUpcoming Congress ECPS MJCSM Preparation Courses ContactESSM - European Society for Sexual Medicine c/o RSM UKCentral Square
5th floor, 29 Wellington Street Leeds West Yorkshire LS1 4DL United Kingdom Join the conversationTwitter Facebook Instagram LinkedIn Youtube
Scroll back to top
X
This site uses cookies to offer you a better browser experience. By using our website you are consenting to our use of cookies in accordance with our Cookie Policy. In addition, Google Analytics will be used with your consent to enhance the user experience in the future. More information can be found here.Ok, allow Google AnalyticsOk, but don't allow Google Analytics
